Register of the C. F. Remer papers
Hoover Institution Archives
C. F. Remer papers
1915-1967
72016
Hoover Institution Archives
40 manuscript boxes, 4 card file boxes, 7 envelopes, 1 album box, 6 phonorecords 18.0 linear feet
Correspondence, writings, notes, studies, speeches, clippings, and printed matter relating to the political and economic development of the Far East, especially China. Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
Remer, C. F. (Charles Frederick), 1889-
Access
Collection open for research. Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items, computer media, and digital files. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos, films, or digital files during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1972.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Alternate Forms Available
Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
Biographical Note
1889 born, Young America, Minnesota
1908 B.A., University of Minnesota
1917-1922 Professor of Economics, St. John's University, Shanghai, China
1923 Ph.D., economics, Harvard University
1924-1928 Professor of Economics, Williams College
1926 author, Foreign Trade of China
1928-1959 Professor of Economics, University of Michigan
1933 co-author, A Study of Chinese Boycotts
1933 co-author, Foreign Investments in China
1938-1939 Director, Geneva Research Center, Geneva, Switzerland
1941-1944 Chief, Far East Division, Research and Analysis Branch, Office of Strategic Services
1944-1945 Advisor, Far Eastern Investment and Finance, U.S. Department of State
1956 author, Japanese Economics, A Guide to Reference and Research Materials
1956 author, Coal Production in Communist China
1959 co-author, Three Essays on the International Economics of Communist China
1961 author, Trade Agreements of Communist China
China--Economic conditions.; China--Politics and government.; China.; East Asia--Economic conditions.; East Asia--Politics and government.; East Asia.; Phonorecords.
- Correspondence, 1917-1966
  - Mailing lists (Box 1)
  - 1917-1929
  - 1930-1939
  - 1940-1949
  - 1950-1959
  - 1960-1966
  - Application for Fulbright Fellowship to lecture in Taiwan, 1964-1965 (Box 2)
  - Family correspondence
  - Hong Kong trip, 1961
  - Mah, Feng-hwa
  - Nanyang University (Singapore)
  - Personal
  - Rockefeller Foundation
  - Taussing, Frank W.
  - VISTA
- Writings and Research Projects, 1915-1964
  Scope and Contents note
  Manuscripts, drafts, research notes, correspondence, book reviews, clippings, and printed matter, relating to C.F. Remer's writings and research projects, arranged chronologically by year of publication or composition.
  - Book reviews by C.F. Remer (Box 3)
  - Relation of Christian Missions in China to Practical Sociology, 1915
  - Certain Related Phenomena, International Trade Under Silver, 1926
  - Foreign Trade of China, book reviews, 1926
  - Study of Chinese Boycotts, book reviews, 1933
  - Foreign Investments in China, 1933
    - Introduction for a later reprint
    - Manuscript and notes
    - Book reviews
  - International Investment in the Far East and Suggestions for Research, 1939
  - Investments in Kind, 1939
  - Economics and War, 1940
  - Michigan and the Reciprocal Trade Agreements, 1940
  - Research in International Economic Relations, 1940
  - Papers and Reference Documents on U.S. Economic Relations with China, 1945
  - Economic Reconstruction in the Far East, 1946
  - International Entrepreneur Investments, Project, 1947
    - Manuscript copy of study
    - Description of project, financial statement, and index to files (Box 4)
    - Organization and suggestions for chapters
    - Drafts of chapters 1-2
    - Drafts of chapters 3-5 (Box 5)
    - Drafts of chapters 6-7 (Box 6)
    - Drafts of chapters 11-13
    - Drafts of chapters 11-13 (Box 7)
    - Drafts of chapters 14-19
    - Drafts of chapters 17-18 (Box 8)
    - Drafts of appendix
    - July draft, chapters 1-17
    - Subject file
      - Bibliography
      - General outlines
      - General outlines (Box 9)
      - Methodology, terminology, classification
      - Theory
      - Business organization
      - International cartels
      - Population and migration
      - Colonies
      - Raw materials
      - Raw materials (Box 10)
      - Trade and exchange restrictions
      - Nationalism
      - Investment in kind
      - Legal questions
      - New and undeveloped countries
      - Business cycle
      - Investments and course of trade
      - Conversations in Europe
      - Suggestions for volume
      - Large enterprises
      - March trip
      - May conference
      - Short and medium term investments
      - Industries
    - Area file (Box 11)
      - World and general
      - Van Zealand report
      - British Empire
      - United States (Box 12)
        - U.S. capital exported
        - U.S. capital imported
        - U.S. Department of Commerce
        - Effect of the War, 1939-1945
        - Export-Import Bank
        - Hawaii (Box 13)
        - Philippines
        - Porto Rico
      - France
      - French Indo-China
      - Belgium
      - Holland
      - Dutch East Indies
      - Germany
      - Germany (Box 14)
      - Switzerland
      - Norway
      - Sweden
      - Denmark
      - Finland
      - Italy
      - Ethiopia
      - Spain and Portugal
      - Austria
      - Czechoslovakia
      - Hungary
      - Yugoslavia (Box 15)
      - Rumania
      - Bulgaria
      - Albania
      - Greece
      - Poland
      - Lithuania
      - Estonia
      - Latvia
      - U.S.S.R.
      - Mexico
      - Cuba
      - Brazil
      - Argentina
      - Chile (Box 16)
      - Other Latin America
      - Japan
      - China
      - Manchuria
      - Siam
      - Turkey
      - Persia, Irak, Palestine
      - Egypt
      - Other Africa
    - Miscellaneous (Box 17)
      - Area notebooks
      - Attitudes toward foreign investment
      - Branch plants in U.S. Experience
      - Capital importing areas
      - Cartels
      - Clippings
      - Cross investments
      - Direct Foreign Investments, by E. Liefmann-Keil
      - Printed matter (Box 18)
      - Printed matter (Box 19)
      - Pure Theory of Trade between Economics Related by Entrepreneur Investments, by Hebbard
      - Reasons for investment
      - Related studies
      - Research note cards
      - Research notes (Box 20)
  - Administration of Foreign Affairs and Overseas Operations of the U.S. Government -- Economic Reporting, 1951
  - Coal Production in Communist China, 1956
    - Published copies
    - Manuscript drafts
    - Notes
    - Correspondence
  - International Economics of Communist China, 1959 (Box 21)
    - Book reviews
    - Outlines
    - Bibliographies
    - Questions
    - Drafts of chapters and information file
      - General doctrine
      - History
      - Chinese communism before 1949
      - Constitutional basis
      - Features of trade
      - Conduct of trade
      - Trade statistics
      - Trade statistics (Box 22)
      - Trade statistics (Box 23)
      - Trade with communist countries
      - Trade with non-communist countries
      - Trade with non-communist countries (Box 24)
      - Hong Kong
      - Overseas Chinese
      - Balance of payments
      - Domestic economy
      - Domestic economy (Box 25)
      - Domestic economy (Box 26)
      - Political and strategic aspects
  - International Economics Project, Center for Chinese Studies (Berkeley, California), 1959-1960 (Box 27)
    - Administration records
    - Financial records
    - Personnel records
    - List of folders in research files
    - Research papers
      - Trade Agreements of Communist China, by C.F. Remer
      - Recent Efforts at Coordinated Planning in the Soviet Bloc, by Oleg Hoeffding
      - Financing Public Investment in Communist China, by Feng-hwa Mah
      - Review of Choh-ming Li's Economic Development of Communist China, by R. Moorstein
    - Research materials
    - Bibliography
    - Information file
      - Organization and means of dealing with international trade
      - Trade statistics
      - Balance of international payments (Box 28)
      - Remittances from overseas Chinese
      - External value of the yuan
      - Terms of trade
      - Trade agreements
      - Policy
  - International Aspects of Economic Development as a Field of Research, 1961
  - Japanese Reparations, Two Contrasting Periods, 1964
    - Manuscripts
    - Correspondence
    - Notes
    - Printed matter
  - A New Approach to the Study of Chinese Communism, undated (Box 29)
  - Preparedness and the Far East, undated
  - Economic Development of Japan as a Basis for Cooperation in Research, undated
  - Revolution and Economic Development in the Mainland of China, undated
  - Some Notes upon the Economic Thought of the Hebrews, undated
- Speeches and Lectures, 1928-1962
  Transcripts of classroom lectures and speeches, drafts, and notes, arranged as listed.
  - Classroom lectures and notes, 1940-1961
    - Economics 141, International Economic Relations, 1940-1941 (Box 29)
    - Economics 142, International Trade, 1940-1941
    - Economics 144, Far Eastern Economic Problems, 1948
    - Economics 145, International Trade of China, 1948-1957 (Box 30)
    - Economics, 245, International Economics of the Far East, 1953-1958
    - Economics 246, International Capital Movements, 1955
    - Economics 142, United States and International Policy, 1957
    - Anthropology 293, Integrated Course on Japan, 1957 (Box 31)
    - Asian Studies 602, Japanese Industrial Development, 1961
  - Equilibrium in International Trade Theory, 1928
  - An Economic Approach to International Relations, 1932
  - International Aspects of the Depression, 1932
  - Miscellaneous lectures on the Far East, 1933-1940
  - War Debts and American Policy, 1933
  - Address before the Annual Conference of University Social Science Research Organizations, 1938
  - The War in the Far East, 1941
  - Postwar Economic Development of China, 1944
  - American Interest in the Economic Future of the Pacific, 1946
  - Problem of American Assistance to Underdeveloped Areas, 1949
  - Absorption of Foreign Capital in Japan's Economic Development, 1952
  - Terms of Trade, 1961
  - My Early Days in China, 1962
  - Appraising the External Economic Relations of Communist China, undated
  - Economic Aspects of the Far Eastern Situation, undated
  - Economic Reconstruction in the Far East, undated
  - Professors in Washington, undated
  - Role of the University in Economic Research, undated
  - The School as a Social Agency from the Viewpoint of the Economist, undated
  - Miscellaneous lectures on the characteristics of economic development
  - Miscellaneous lectures and lecture notes
- Subject File, 1921-1967
  Reports, studies, conference papers, correspondence, notes, clippings, and printed matter, arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Americans for Reappraisal of Far Eastern Policy (Box 32)
  - Bibliographies and lists of books ordered
  - China (Nationalist), 1921-1961
    - Agriculture
    - American cultural influence upon
    - Army
    - Economic development
    - Extraterritoriality
    - Famine relief, 1921-1922
    - Finance
    - Foreign investment (Box 33)
    - General
    - Industry
    - Lytton Report
    - Politics and government
    - Railroads
    - Reconstruction and relief
    - Social and cultural life
    - Trade (Box 34)
    - United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration work, 1945
  - China (Communist), 1949-1967
    - Admission to United Nations
    - Agriculture
    - Bibliography
    - Economic development (Box 35)
    - Foreign relations
    - Foreign trade
    - Industry
    - Labor
    - Money and banking
    - Natural resources
    - Personal narratives
    - Political, social, and psychological aspects
    - Population
    - Technology
  - Dachau and Buchenwald, A Report of Facts (Box 36)
  - East and west relations
  - Economic development of underdeveloped areas
  - Economics, miscellaneous printed matter
  - European Common Market
  - Institute of International Studies (Berkeley, California)
  - Institute of Pacific Relations
    - Circulating memoranda, 1932
    - Lucknow Conference, 1950
      - Notes and correspondence
      - Conference papers and studies
    - Miscellaneous pamphlets, lists, and circulars
  - International Bank for Reconstruction and Development (Box 37)
  - Japan
    - Economic development
    - Foreign investments
    - Foreign trade
    - Income of Niike
    - Industrialization
    - Internal politics and culture
    - Relations with China
    - Relations with United States
  - Kaldor, Nicholas, Characteristics of Economic Development (Box 38)
  - Kennedy, John F., speech on U.S. military and diplomatic policies before Congress, 1958
  - Macro-economic theory
  - Nutter, Warren G., pamphlet on Soviet industrial growth
  - Philippines
  - Rapport, William E.
  - Sharfman, Leo
  - Smith, Bruce L.R., pamphlet on Berlin government
  - Southeast Asia
  - Union of Soviet Socialist Republics, economy
  - United Nations Economic Commission for Asia and the Far East
  - University of Michigan
  - Vitae sheets on students
  - Ward, Frederick Townsend
  - Wu, Chun-hsi, Remittance to Communist China
- Photographs, circa 1920-1930
  - 102 postcards and photos of daily life and cultural sites in China, circa 1920 (Envelope A)
  - 102 postcards and photos of daily life and cultural sites in China cont. (oversize items), circa 1920 (Envelope mB)
  - 1 album of 30 photos of daily life and cultural sites in China. Entitled "Picturesque China," by D. Mennie, circa 1920 (Album fC)
  - 55 photos of the famine relief work in China, 1921 January-February (Envelope D)
  - 1 photo of Chiang Kai-shek, circa 1930 (Envelope mE)
  - 6 photos of C. F. Remer and his professional associates, undated (Envelope F)
  - 56 photos of C. F. Remer, his personal friends, and his family, undated (Envelope G)
  - 1 photo of Yuan-ping Sha, undated (Envelope H)
- Miscellany
  Certificates of award, degrees, memorabilia, clippings, printed matter, notebooks, and card files.
  - Awards and degrees (Box 39)
  - Biographical file
  - Memorabilia
  - Newspaper clippings
  - Notebooks of C.F. Remer
  - Printed matter
  - Scrapbook of clippings and memorabilia
  - Card bibliography file on Nationalist China (Box 40)
  - Card bibliography file on Communist China (Box 41-43)
  - Increment to collection (Box 44)
    - C-Correspondence
    - F-Correspondence
    - Foreign Affairs TV Series
    - H-Correspondence
    - Hebbard, W. L.
    - Ho-Correspondence
    - L-Correspondence
    - Liu, Vincent
    - Lockwood, William, Jr.
    - M-Correspondence
    - N-O-Correspondence
    - P-Q-Correspondence
    - Polk, Judd
    - Rockefeller Foundation
    - S-Correspondence
    - Si-Correspondence
    - Social Science Research Council
    - State, Department of
    - Thomas, Philip S.
    - United Nations
    - W-Correspondence
    - Miscellaneous correspondence
- Declassified U.S. government records, 1930-1944
  - 2018 release of declassified records, 1930-1944 (Reading room workstation)